Wei.
وي.
What should we do now?
ماذا يجب علينا أن نفعل الآن؟
Now Su Changming has also gotten involved.
والآن أصبح سو تشانغ مينغ متورطًا أيضًا.
Things are getting more and more complicated.
الأمور أصبحت أكثر تعقيدا.
I told you long ago
لقد قلت لك منذ زمن طويل
that woman can't be trusted.
لا يمكن الوثوق بتلك المرأة.
However,
لكن،
he didn't tell Chen Jingbian
لم يخبر تشين جينغبيان
about your deception.
عن خداعك.
That means there's still room to maneuver.
وهذا يعني أنه لا يزال هناك مجال للمناورة.
I'll figure something out.
سأكتشف شيئا ما.
What are you going to do?
ما كنت تنوي القيام به؟
Don't do anything rash.
لا تفعل أي شيء متهور.
The simplest solution now
الحل الأبسط الآن
is to hand over both the person and the sword to Su Changming.
هو تسليم الشخص والسيف إلى سو تشانغ مينغ.
We might even be able to use him
ربما نكون قادرين على استخدامه
to get the Night Firefly Map.
للحصول على خريطة Night Firefly.
Li Ling.
لي لينغ.
Hey.
يا.
Are you even listening to me?
هل تستمع لي حقا؟
The Tang army is about to enter Chang'an City!
جيش تانغ على وشك دخول مدينة تشانغآن!
The Tang army is entering Chang'an City!
جيش تانغ يدخل مدينة تشانغآن!
Don't run so fast!
لا تركض بسرعة!
Sister! Yu!
أختي! يو!
Sister, someone's coming!
أختي، هناك شخص قادم!
Yezi, come here.
مهلا، تعال هنا.
Don't be afraid.
لا تخف.
He's my friend
إنه صديقي
and he's with the Tang army.
وهو مع جيش تانغ.
Why are you standing there?
لماذا تقف هناك؟
Come in quickly. We're having saozi noodles today.
تفضلوا بالدخول. لدينا نودلز ساوزي اليوم.
No help, no food for you.
لا مساعدة، لا طعام لك.
All right.
حسنًا.
Come on, try my cooking.
تعال، جرب طبخي.
How is it? Tasty?
كيف هو؟ لذيذ؟
Delicious!
لذيذ!
Eat slowly.
تناول الطعام ببطء.
It's so good!
إنه جيد جدًا!
I love
انا احب
these saozi noodles you make.
هذه معكرونة الساوزي التي تصنعها.
If you like them,
إذا كنت تحبهم،
I'll make them for you every day.
سأصنعها لك كل يوم.
Nonsense!
هراء!
You're my deputy commander now,
أنت نائب القائد الآن،
not some cook.
ليس طباخًا.
Use that time to train soldiers instead.
استخدم هذا الوقت لتدريب الجنود بدلا من ذلك.
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي.
You haven't taken a wife yet, have you?
لم تتزوج بعد، أليس كذلك؟
Not yet.
ليس بعد.
I've thought of a perfect solution.
لقد فكرت في الحل الأمثل.
I have a daughter named Yinniang.
عندي ابنة اسمها ينيانغ.
Though she has a bit of a temper,
على الرغم من أنها غاضبة بعض الشيء،
she's quite beautiful,
إنها جميلة جدًا
and very clever too.
وذكي جداً أيضاً.
Whoever marries her will be a lucky man.
من يتزوجها سيكون رجلا محظوظا.
If you have what it takes to win her over,
إذا كان لديك ما يلزم لكسبها،
then I could enjoy these noodles every day.
ثم أستطيع الاستمتاع بهذه المعكرونة كل يوم.
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر.
All right.
حسنًا.
I suddenly feel these noodles smell even better now.
فجأة أشعر أن رائحة هذه المعكرونة أصبحت أفضل الآن.
This time when you went back,
هذه المرة عندما عدت،
it's fortunate that Chen Jingbian didn't suspect you.
من حسن الحظ أن تشين جينغبيان لم يشك بك.
By the way, what about me?
بالمناسبة، ماذا عني؟
What does he plan to do?
ماذا يخطط أن يفعل؟
Has he sent anyone to find you?
هل أرسل أحدا للبحث عنك؟
Even if he doesn't look for me,
حتى لو لم يبحث عني،
I'll find a way to go back.
سأجد طريقة للعودة.
After all, he can't stop taking his medicine.
بعد كل شيء، فهو لا يستطيع التوقف عن تناول دوائه.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
did you notice the color at the bottom of his eyes?
هل لاحظت اللون في أسفل عينيه؟
The color of his eyes?
لون عينيه؟
I didn't notice that.
لم ألاحظ ذلك.
Why?
لماذا؟
It seems it's not time yet,
يبدو أنه لم يحن الوقت بعد
otherwise the whites of his eyes should be noticeably yellow.
وإلا فإن بياض عينيه يجب أن يكون أصفر بشكل ملحوظ.
I didn't tell you before,
لم أخبرك من قبل
I tampered with his medicine.
لقد تلاعبت بدوائه.
I've been controlling the dosage to avoid detection.
لقد كنت أتحكم في الجرعة لتجنب الكشف.
You mean...
هل تقصد...
I was worried that even if we got the Firefly Map,
كنت أشعر بالقلق من أنه حتى لو حصلنا على خريطة Firefly،
it would be hard to tell if it's real.
سيكون من الصعب معرفة ما إذا كان هذا حقيقيًا.
So you're controlling him with the medicine.
لذلك أنت تسيطر عليه بالدواء.
According to my calculations,
وفقا لحساباتي،
it should be almost time now.
يجب أن يكون الوقت قد حان الآن تقريبًا.
I see.
أرى.
You've planned everything.
لقد خططت لكل شيء.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Yin Niang.
يين نيانغ.
Young Master.
السيد الشاب.
That Li Ling,
هذا لي لينغ،
he won't be causing trouble behind our backs, will he?
لن يسبب مشاكل خلف ظهورنا، أليس كذلك؟
It's too late for him to do anything now.
لقد فات الأوان بالنسبة له للقيام بأي شيء الآن.
They're already like meat
إنهم بالفعل مثل اللحوم
on a chopping board, ready to be sliced.
على لوح التقطيع، جاهزة للتقطيع.
Young Master, a letter has arrived.
سيدي الشاب، لقد وصلت رسالة.
You see?
هل ترى؟
They still have to come begging to me.
لا زال عليهم أن يأتوا إليّ متوسلين.
Miss Yu.
السيدة يو.
Here's the medicine prepared for you.
وهنا الدواء المعد لك.
Please wait.
انتظر من فضلك.
When we rescued Qi the other day,
عندما أنقذنا تشي في اليوم الآخر،
I spoke inappropriately.
لقد تحدثت بشكل غير لائق.
Please don't take it to heart, Miss Yu.
من فضلك لا تأخذي هذا الأمر على محمل الجد، يا آنسة يو.
You're too kind, Mr. Zhuang.
أنت لطيف جدًا، سيد تشوانغ.
Wait.
انتظر.
Is there something else?
هل هناك شيئا آخر؟
Li Ling.
لي لينغ.
Has he told you anything?
هل قال لك شيئا؟
Told me what?
قال لي ماذا؟
I knew it.
كنت أعرف.
It would be like this.
سيكون مثل هذا.
Mr. Zhuang,
السيد تشوانغ،
has something happened?
هل حدث شيء؟
Li Ling is just like that.
لي لينغ هي مثل ذلك تماما.
No matter what happens,
بغض النظر عما يحدث،
he always bears it alone.
فهو يتحملها دائمًا بمفرده.
Chen Jingbian was the one who summoned Su Changming.
تشين جينغبيان هو الذي استدعى سو تشانغ مينغ.
Su Changming
سو تشانغمينغ
is just a profit-seeking opportunist.
هو مجرد انتهازي يسعى للربح.
To obtain the Night Firefly Scroll,
للحصول على مخطوطة Firefly الليلية،
he has agreed to help Chen Jingbian hold Chang'an.
وقد وافق على مساعدة تشين جينغبيان في السيطرة على تشانغآن.
When that happens,
عندما يحدث ذلك،
there will surely be another bloodbath.
من المؤكد أنه سيكون هناك حمام دم آخر.
The Tang soldiers
جنود تانغ
and countless civilians in the city will suffer and die.
وسوف يعاني ويموت عدد لا يحصى من المدنيين في المدينة.
Miss Nongyu
الآنسة نونجيو
what are
ما هي
you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
As a secret agent of the imperial court,
كعميل سري للبلاط الإمبراطوري،
I've spent half my life undercover.
لقد قضيت نصف حياتي متخفيًا.
Now when our nation is in peril,
والآن عندما أصبحت أمتنا في خطر،
I've been given this critical mission.
لقد تم تكليفي بهذه المهمة الحرجة.
I've weathered many storms before
لقد تجاوزت العديد من العواصف من قبل
and survived them all on my own.
ونجوت من كل ذلك بمفردي.
But this time,
ولكن هذه المرة،
this crucial mission to recapture Chang'an...
هذه المهمة الحاسمة لاستعادة تشانغآن...
I...
أنا...
I truly don't know what to do anymore.
أنا حقا لا أعرف ماذا أفعل بعد الآن.
Master Zhuang, please get up first.
سيد تشوانغ، من فضلك قم أولا.
Since Chang'an fell,
منذ سقوط تشانغآن،
our fellow undercover agents...
زملاؤنا العملاء السريون...
Some died,
مات بعضهم
some were injured.
وأصيب بعضهم.
Now only Li Ling and I remain,
الآن بقي أنا ولي لينغ فقط،
still struggling to hold on.
لا يزال يكافح من أجل التمسك.
Whether we can successfully retake the city
هل يمكننا استعادة المدينة بنجاح؟
depends entirely on intelligence transmission.
يعتمد كليًا على نقل المعلومات الاستخبارية.
Miss Nongyu.
الآنسة نونجيو.
We cannot allow Chen Jingbian
لا يمكننا السماح لـ تشين جينغبيان
to cause more trouble with the Firefly Map.
لإحداث المزيد من المشاكل مع خريطة Firefly.
Master Zhuang,
المعلم تشوانغ،
please stand up when you speak.
من فضلك قف عندما تتحدث.
Miss Yu.
السيدة يو.
About your background...
عن خلفيتك...
Li Ling has already told me.
لقد أخبرتني لي لينغ بالفعل.
I know you're General Feng's daughter.
أعرف أنك ابنة الجنرال فينج.
General Feng spent his entire life in military service,
لقد أمضى الجنرال فينج حياته كلها في الخدمة العسكرية،
all so that the people of the Tang Dynasty
كل ذلك حتى يتمكن شعب أسرة تانغ
could live in peace.
أستطيع أن أعيش بسلام.
As his daughter,
كإبنته،
you must
يجب عليك أن
also understand what's right and just.
وفهم أيضًا ما هو الصواب والعادل.
I know I shouldn't say these things,
أعلم أنه لا ينبغي لي أن أقول هذه الأشياء،
but for the sake of our Tang Dynasty,
ولكن من أجل أسرة تانغ،
for all its people,
لجميع شعبها،
for Li Ling...
للي لينغ...
I beg you, Miss Feng,
أتوسل إليك يا آنسة فينج،
to distract Su Changming
لتشتيت انتباه سو تشانغمينغ
and retrieve the Night Firefly Map.
واسترداد خريطة Night Firefly.
Li Ling.
لي لينغ.
Where are my sword and the woman?
أين سيفي والمرأة؟
After all this talk,
بعد كل هذا الحديث،
this is your real purpose.
هذا هو هدفك الحقيقي.
You want me to distract Su Changming
تريد مني أن ألهي سو تشانغ مينغ
in exchange for the Firefly Map.
في مقابل خريطة Firefly.
You just want me to throw myself at him.
أنت فقط تريد مني أن أرمي نفسي عليه.
Miss Nongyu,
الآنسة نونجيو،
you're the only one who can do it now.
أنت الوحيد الذي يمكنه فعل ذلك الآن.
Young Master, you're back. Someone is waiting for you.
يا سيدي الشاب، لقد عدت. هناك من ينتظرك.
I heard that only if both I and the sword belong to you,
سمعت أنه فقط إذا كنت أنا والسيف ملكًا لك،
will you be willing to help the Tang Dynasty.
هل ستكون على استعداد لمساعدة أسرة تانغ؟
Can you keep your word?
هل تستطيع الوفاء بكلمتك؟
I'm just a bandit.
أنا مجرد لص.
I do terrible things
أنا أفعل أشياء فظيعة
and break my promises.
وأخلف وعودي.
Do you think I keep my word?
هل تعتقد أنني أحافظ على كلمتي؟
Since you're here,
بما أنك هنا،
you might as well sleep with me.
من الأفضل أن تنام معي.
Show me all those skills
أرني كل تلك المهارات
you used to please Li Ling.
لقد اعتدت على إرضاء لي لينغ.
Hit me.
ضربني.
Go ahead, hit me.
تفضل، اضربني.
Last time I treated you this way,
آخر مرة عاملتك بهذه الطريقة،
you were completely unwilling.
لقد كنت غير راغب تماما.
Why is it that this time
لماذا هذه المرة
you're playing hard to get?
أنت تلعب دور الصعب الحصول عليه؟
Because you've already applied
لأنك قمت بالتقديم بالفعل
poison to your lips.
السم على شفتيك.
Try again.
حاول ثانية.
I won't fight anymore. I surrender.
لن أقاتل بعد الآن. أنا أستسلم.
No more fighting?
لا مزيد من القتال؟
Then accept your loss.
ثم تقبل خسارتك.
Since you've lost,
منذ أن خسرت،
you should act like it.
ينبغي عليك التصرف على هذا الأساس.
Where are my sword and woman?
أين سيفي وامرأتي؟
You will never get the person or the sword.
لن تحصل أبدًا على الشخص أو السيف.
You...
أنت...
If I can't even protect
إذا لم أستطع حتى الحماية
the person I love and my benefactor's relic,
الشخص الذي أحبه وآثار فاعل خيري،
then I'm worse than a scoundrel.
إذاً أنا أسوأ من الوغد.
Su Changming,
سو تشانغمينغ,
don't you understand even now?
هل لم تفهم حتى الآن؟
Even if you get the person and the sword,
حتى لو حصلت على الشخص والسيف،
you still won't be the winner.
لن تكون الفائز بعد.
Ridiculous.
سخيف.
I, Su Changming, have never lost.
أنا، سو تشانغ مينغ، لم أخسر أبدًا.
Deep down, you know very well
في أعماقك، أنت تعرف جيدًا
that even if you keep Nongyu by your side,
حتى لو أبقيت نونغيو بجانبك،
you will never truly have her.
لن تحصل عليها أبدًا حقًا.
Because...
لأن...
She doesn't belong to anyone.
إنها لا تنتمي إلى أحد.
She only belongs to herself.
إنها تنتمي لنفسها فقط.
Actually,
في الحقيقة،
what you really want
ما تريده حقا
is my life, isn't it?
هذه هي حياتي، أليس كذلك؟
Fine then.
حسنا إذن.
I'll give it to you.
سأعطيك إياها.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
I'll give you my life,
سأعطيك حياتي
but I have one condition.
ولكن لدي شرط واحد.
You and the Guantian Society
أنت وجمعية غوانتيان
must join the Tang army.
يجب أن ينضم إلى جيش تانغ.
Li Ling,
لي لينغ,
have you gone mad out of desperation?
هل جننت من شدة اليأس؟
I lead my brothers to enjoy the good life
أرشد إخوتي إلى التمتع بالحياة الطيبة
and live freely.
والعيش بحرية.
Why would I be foolish enough
لماذا أكون أحمقًا بما فيه الكفاية؟
to join the Tang army?
للانضمام إلى جيش تانغ؟
For honor.
من أجل الشرف.
Honor?
شرف؟
You killed your commander and betrayed your master for glory.
لقد قتلت قائدك وخنت سيدك من أجل المجد.
What right do you have to talk about honor?
ما هو الحق الذي لديك للحديث عن الشرف؟
What I'm doing now
ماذا أفعل الآن
is the same as what Feng Jianye did
هو نفس ما فعله فينج جياني
when he willingly offered his own head
عندما عرض رأسه طواعية
years ago.
منذ سنوات.
Stop glorifying yourself.
توقف عن تمجيد نفسك.
After Tongguan fell,
بعد سقوط تونغجوان،
the Emperor fled west,
فر الإمبراطور غربًا،
Chang'an was captured,
تم القبض على تشانغآن،
and the Great Tang was in peril.
وكانت مملكة تانغ العظيمة في خطر.
General Feng
الجنرال فنغ
wanted me to go undercover beside Chen Jingbian
أرادني أن أذهب متخفيًا بجانب تشين جينغبيان
to obtain the Night Firefly Map.
للحصول على خريطة Night Firefly.
That's why he chose to die,
ولهذا السبب اختار الموت.
sacrificing himself willingly.
التضحية بنفسه طوعا.
All these lies you're telling
كل هذه الأكاذيب التي تقولها
are just to absolve yourself of guilt.
فقط لتبرئة نفسك من الذنب.
You can cut off my head, Li Ling's head, right now.
يمكنك قطع رأسي، رأس لي لينغ، الآن.
What are you waiting for?
ماذا تنتظر؟
Yiyu
ممكن
Xie Zheng
شيه تشنغ
Yan Zhirui
يان زيروي
Kang Sunrui
كانغ سونروي
Ying Lu
ينغ لو
Tong Liu Hao Xiao
تونغ ليو هاو شياو
Liu Wang
ليو وانغ
Jiajia Ningtao Jiaying Xidou Rong
جياجيا نينغتاو جياينغ شيدو رونغ
Jiajia Ningtao Jia
جياجيا نينغتاو جيا
Jiajia Ningtao Jiaying Xidou Rongjing
جياجيا نينغتاو جياينغ شيدو رونغجينغ
Xi Liu Lu
شي ليو لو
Li
الذي - التي
Assistant
مساعد
Sheng Lanfeng Tao
شنغ لانفنغ تاو
Media Limited Broadcasting Co., Ltd.
شركة ميديا ​​المحدودة للبث
Limited Company
شركة محدودة
Limited
محدود